A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away...
Star Wars is a adventure, action, science fiction film directed by George Lucas.
Princess Leia is captured and held hostage by the evil Imperial
forces in their effort to take over the galactic Empire.
Venturesome Luke Skywalker and dashing captain Han Solo team together with the loveable robot duo R2-D2
and C-3PO to rescue the beautiful princess and restore peace and justice in the Empire.
Luke Skywalker, played by Mark Hamill.
Han Solo, played by Harrison Ford.
Princess Leia Organa, played by Carrie Fisher.
Grand Moff Tarkin, played by Peter Cushing.
Obi-Wan "Ben" Kenobi, played by Alec Guinness.
C-3PO, played by Anthony Daniels.
Star Wars (later retitled Star Wars: Episode IV – A New Hope) is a 1977 American epic space
opera film written and directed by George Lucas, produced by Lucasfilm Ltd.
and released by Twentieth Century-Fox.
It is the first film in the Star Wars franchise and the fourth
chronological chapter of the "Skywalker Saga".
Set in a fictional galaxy under the rule of the tyrannical Galactic Empire, the film follows a resistance
movement, called the Rebel Alliance, that aims to destroy the Empire's ultimate weapon, the Death Star.
When the rebel leader Princess Leia is captured by the Galactic Empire, Luke Skywalker acquires stolen architectural plans for the Death Star and
sets out to rescue her while learning the ways of a metaphysical power known as "the Force" from the Jedi Master Obi-Wan Kenobi.
The cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing, Alec Guinness,
Anthony Daniels, Kenny Baker, Peter Mayhew, David Prowse, and James Earl Jones.
Lucas had the idea for a science fiction film in the vein of Flash Gordon around the time he completed his first film,
THX 1138 (1971), and he began working on a treatment after the release of American Graffiti (1973).
After numerous rewrites, principal photography began in March of 1976 in locations
including Tunisia and Elstree Studios in Hertfordshire, England.
Lucas formed the visual effects company Industrial Light &
Magic to help create the film's visual effects.
Star Wars suffered production difficulties: the cast and crew believed the film
would be a failure, and it went $3 million over budget due to delays.
Few were confident in the film's box office prospects.
It was released in a small number of theaters in the United States on May 25, 1977, and quickly
became a surprise blockbuster, leading to it being expanded to a much wider release.
Star Wars opened to critical acclaim, with
particular praise for its special effects.
It grossed $410 million worldwide during its initial run, surpassing Jaws (1975)
to become the highest-grossing film until the release of E.T.
the Extra-Terrestrial (1982); subsequent releases have
brought its total gross to $775 million.
When adjusted for inflation, Star Wars is the second-highest-grossing film in North America
(behind Gone with the Wind) and the fourth-highest-grossing film of all time.
It received six Academy Awards, two BAFTA Awards, and
thirteen Saturn Awards, among others.
The film has been reissued many times with Lucas' support, including the 1981 reissue giving
the film the subtitle Episode IV – A New Hope, and the 1997 "Special Edition".
The reissues have contained many changes, including new
scenes, visual effects, and dialogue.
Often regarded as one of the greatest and most influential films of all time, Star Wars quickly became a worldwide pop culture phenomenon, launching an
industry of tie-in products, including novels, comics, video games, amusement park attractions and merchandise such as toys, games, and clothing.
It became one of the first 25 films selected by the United States Library of Congress for
preservation in the National Film Registry in 1989, and its soundtrack was added to the U.S.
National Recording Registry in 2004.
The Empire Strikes Back (1980) and Return of the Jedi (1983) followed
Star Wars, rounding out the original Star Wars trilogy.
A prequel trilogy and a sequel trilogy have since been released, in
addition to two standalone films and various television series.
The film explores themes of empire, galaxy, rebellion, android, hermit.
The tone is thought_provoking.